(
"ai_sub_version": "2.8.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"ollama_search": (
"key": "**********"
),
"web_search_tool": "ollama",
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
ONE MOMENT PLEASE
[Title: ONE MOMENT PLEASE]
みんなこんこよー！
Everyone, Kon-koyo!
ホロライブ6期生秘密結社holoXの頭脳、
The brain of Hololive's 6th Gen Secret Society holoX,
博衣こよりだよー！
it's Haku Koyori!
Kon-koyo, everyone!
Sixth generation of Hololive and Brain of holoX,
6th generation of Hololive and Brain of holoX,
my name is Koyori Hakui! Kon-koyo, Kon-koyo!
my name is Haku Koyori! Kon-koyo, Kon-koyo!
ということで、本日はですね、
And so, today...
昨日の夜「何やろうかな」ってぼやいていたんですけど、
I was wondering what to do last night,
急に料理が作りたくなって。
but suddenly I felt like cooking.
そう、いろいろね、「どのゲームやろうか、なんかやるゲームあるかな」って探してたんですけど、
Yeah, I was looking for games to play, wondering if there were any...
最近の悩み。
My recent struggle.
ちょっとあの、単発のゲームが見つからないという悩みを抱えていて、
I've been having trouble finding a short-form game to play,
そう、で、「なんかご飯作ろう」って思ったんですよ。
so I thought, "I'll cook something."
料理配信最近やってないし、
I haven't done a cooking stream lately,
料理配信したいなって思って。
and I wanted to do one.
で、「じゃあ何作る？」っていうのを調べたの。
So I looked into what to make.
まだね、この時はカレーじゃない。
At that point, it wasn't curry yet.
カレーの気分にまだなってないの。
I wasn't in the mood for curry yet.
何作るのが面白いかなって。
I wondered what would be interesting to make.
この前ね、カルボナーラを作りましたけど、
I made carbonara recently,
そういうなんか、
and I wanted something like that...
ドキドキする、初めて作るもの。
Something exciting that I've never made before.
でもなんかできそうだけど、
Something that seems doable,
でもちょっと難しそうみたいなやつ。
but also seems a bit difficult.
「何がいいかな」って思って調べてたんです。
I was thinking about what would be good while searching.
そしたら、思いついたの。
Then, it hit me.
「あ！スパイスカレー作ろう」って。
“Ah! I'll make spice curry!”
スパイスカレーってさ、やっぱりちょっと難しい感じするし、
Spice curry feels a bit difficult, you know?
カレーは作ったことあっても、スパイスカレーは作ったことない。
I've made curry before, but never spice curry.
スパイスから作るカレーってなかなかなね、
Making curry from spices is something...
作ったことないと思うので、みんなも。
I don't think many of you have made it either.
「これはいいんじゃないかな」と思って。
“This might be a good idea,” I thought.
よし、今日はスパイスカレー作ろうって思い、
Alright, I decided to make spice curry today,
人生初めてだからちょっと匂わせておこうっつって、
and since it's a first, I thought I'd drop a hint,
匂わせをしたんですよ、Xで。
so I dropped a hint on X.
「今日は生まれて初めてのことをやろうと思います」。
“Today, I'm going to do something for the first time in my life.”
で、あの時すでにね、サムネも発注している。
And at that time, I had already ordered the thumbnail.
発注しないと間に合わないからね、お急ぎで。
I had to order it quickly, or it wouldn't be ready.
発注していて、そして出かけました。
I had ordered it, and then I went out.
そしたら何か、ココイチさんのコラボが発表されていました！
Then, a collaboration with CoCo Ichi
was announced!
いや流石に、流石にこれは運命だろ！
Seriously, this has to be fate!
マジで何も知らなかった、本当に。
I really had no idea, honestly.
でももう発表されてるってことは、こよりは知らないってことは…
But if it's already been announced,
and I didn't know...
と思っちゃいますけど、でもこれは分かりません。
I can't help but wonder,
but I don't know for sure.
分からないから、公開オーディションだと思って。
Since I don't know,
I'll treat this as a "public audition."
本日は、カレーを頑張って作っていきたいと思います！よし！
Today, I'm going to do my best
to make some curry! Yosh!
はい、マジで何も知らなかった。
Seriously, I had no clue.
こんなことある？なかなかやんない、料理配信。
How could this happen?
I don't do cooking streams often.
バレンタインデー以来ですからね、1ヶ月半ぶりぐらいなんですけど。
It's been about a month and a half
since Valentine's Day.
そんなことある？マジでビックリしたわ。
Coincidence? I was really surprised.
ちなみにココイチさんでは最近、スープカレーとかも出てて...
By the way, CoCo Ichi recently
released a soup curry...
「おお、スープカレーも出てる！」とかね。
"Oh, they have soup curry too!" and so on.
こよりちゃんはスタンダードなやつを、ポークカレー...
I really love the standard pork curry...
甘口0辛で食べるのがすごい好きなので。
at spice level 0, mild.
辛いのが苦手でも、ココイチさんめっちゃ食べるんよ。
Even though I'm not good with spice,
I eat at CoCo Ichi a lot.
だからその辛みを選べるし、甘口を選べるのが本当に素晴らしい。
It's great that you can choose the spice
level and pick mild.
たまたま一昨日食べてたしね。
I actually happened to eat there
the day before yesterday.
一昨日のは、手仕込みチキンカツがこより好きなんだけど...
I usually like the hand-prepared chicken katsu...
手仕込みささみカツっていうのが出てて。
but they had hand-prepared sasami
(chicken breast) katsu.
「わ、ささみって女子嬉しいやつやん！」みたいな感じで。
"Wow, sasami is something girls would love!"
ささみカツに納豆と、ハーフチキン...
So I had sasami katsu with natto,
half chicken...
とハーフ野菜ね。
and half vegetables.
野菜はハーフで頼めるから、ハーフで足しておくと...
You can order half portions of vegetables,
so if I add half...
野菜も取れたような気持ちになって、すごい良いんですよ。
it makes me feel like I've eaten my veggies.
It's great.
っていうので食べておりました。
So that's what I was eating.
ということで本日はですね、初めてのスパイスカレーを作っていきたいと思います！
Anyway, today I'm making spice curry
from scratch for the first time.
何かね、簡単そうだってレシピ見たら。
The recipe looked pretty simple
when I checked it.
行けそうじゃんってなっております。
I feel like I can do this.
ということで配信開始ポストもしたので、リポストよろしくお願いします。
I've posted that the stream is starting,
so please repost it.
ココイチさんが大体素早く届けてくれるから、それも本当にありがたい。
CoCo Ichi delivers quickly,
which I'm very grateful for.
ほなまず、今日作るのは一応レシピを見ながら作るんですけど。
Well then, first, I'll be following a recipe...
すごい人気のレシピを見ております。
a very popular one I found.
初めてでも作れそうなスパイスカレーレシピを見てるんですけど。
It's a spice curry recipe that seems
doable even for beginners.
それにちょっとオリジナルチャートを発動させつつ、やっていきたいと思います。
I'll follow that while adding
my "Original Chart" (twist).
てなわけで、カメラオン行きましょう。ドン！
Alright, let's turn the camera on. Dom!
よく見る、こよりの料理配信で一番最初に出てくるこの玉ねぎ。
A familiar sight at the start of
my cooking streams: an onion.
あ、待って、これ、透明のやつつけた方がいいね。
Oh, wait, I should put on the transparent ones.
玉ねぎ汁が完全にこの布手袋に染み込むところだったわ。
Onion juice was about to soak into
these cloth gloves.
おいしょ、おいしょ。ビニール手袋も付けて...
Heave-ho, heave-ho. Putting on the plastic gloves...
はい、こちら玉ねぎですね。みじん切りにしていきたいと思います。
Here's the onion. I'm going to mince it.
待って、何個だ？えーと、1/2個かな。
Wait, how many? I think half an onion.
まずこれ、頭を取って。
First, cut off the top.
うまく取れない。よし、頭を捨てて。
It's not coming off easily. Okay, throwing away the top.
ちなみに今日ちこよは野放しにしてるんだけど、いないな。
By the way, Chi-Koyo is wandering around today,
but I don't see her.
玉ねぎ危険だからね、気を付けないとね。
Onions are dangerous for cats,
so I have to be careful.
はい、お尻も取って。
Alright, cutting off the bottom too.
猫の手はちょっとこよりちゃんできないんで。
I can't do the "cat hand" (claw grip), so...
絶対に切らない位置に手を置く。はい、1/2個ですね。
I'll place my hand where I definitely won't cut it.
Half an onion!
ということで、これはクレラップに入れておこう。
I'll put this half in plastic wrap.
水っぽい手。クレラップに半分包んでおいて、ママーテにあげよう。
My hands are watery. Wrapping the other half
for Mama-te.
料理配信の残りは大体ママーテのもとに行く。
Leftovers from my cooking streams
usually go to her.
さあちょっと久しぶりかな、カルボナーラの時は野菜を切るシーンがなかったので。
It's been a while since you've seen my knife skills...
こよりちゃんの久々の料理捌きをお見せすることになるかと思います。
since the Carbonara stream didn't have much
vegetable cutting.
みじん切りは、まず細く切って。
For mincing, first I'll slice it thinly.
今日、音大きいな。
The sound is quite loud today.
涙が出ないように。
I hope my eyes don't water.
これね、切る時に玉ねぎの成分が...
When you cut an onion, its components...
空中をね、舞うんですよね。
dance in the air, don't they?
それが目に入るから涙が出るっていう。
That's why your eyes water when they get in.
目に入ると痛くなるから...
Because if it gets in my eyes, it'll hurt...
切る時は目を瞑る。
When I cut, I close my eyes.
よいしょ。
There we go.
こうして...
Like this...
ほ。ほ。
Ho. Ho.
まぁ最終的にはみじんになるから...
Well, eventually it'll be minced, so...
でもこれギュってしてるから...
But I'm pressing down firmly, so...
猫の手してるから、切れることは絶対にない。
with a "cat paw" grip, there's no way I'll cut myself.
この親指より左にしかないから指は。
My fingers are only to the left of this thumb.
猫の手マジで分からんねん。
I really don't get the "cat paw" thing.
えーと。よし！
Let's see. Okay!
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
これもう行けないな、これ以上。だからここで切っとこう。
I can't go any further with this. So I'll cut it here.
ほ！ほ！オッケー。
Ho! Ho! Okay.
そしたらこれをみじんにするかな。
Now, I guess I'll mince this.
一回縦にして... よいしょ。
First, cut it lengthwise... There we go.
終わり良ければ全て良しだから。多分ここはオーディションに含まれない。
All's well that ends well. This part probably isn't part of the audition.
ここはね、カレーの前の段階だから。大丈夫。
This is just the pre-curry stage. It's fine.
包丁は使えても使えなくても、最終的にカレーになってればそれでいい。
Whether you're good with a knife or not, as long as it becomes curry in the end, it's fine.
ほ。ほ。よいしょ。お、いいんじゃない？
Ho. Ho. There we go. Oh, isn't this good?
みじんっぽくなってきたんじゃない？よいしょ。
Doesn't it look minced now? There we go.
まぁ最終的にね、小さくなればいいかな。
Well, eventually, as long as it gets small, I guess.
今はザク切りなんだけど...
It's just roughly chopped right now, but...
この後あの、三刀流みたいな感じでこの包丁が舞うから大丈夫。
after this, this knife is going to dance like a "three-sword style" user, so it'll be fine.
ふ。
Phew.
え？これってみじん切りだったの？
Eh? Was this supposed to be mincing?
大丈夫。今から。今からみじん切りになるから。
It's fine. Starting now. It'll become minced starting now.
最終的にさ、みじんになってりゃいいわけよ. オッケー？
In the end, as long as it's minced, it works. Okay?
待って、この包丁で切ってる横に大さじ小さじ置いてるの絶対間違いだ。
Wait, having these measuring spoons right next to where I'm cutting is definitely a mistake.
たまねぎの汁が大さじの中に入り込んで...
The onion juice is getting into the tablespoon...
これから粉ものばかり量るのにさ。よいしょ。
and I'm about to measure a lot of powders. There we go.
ちなみにですね、レシピにあるスパイスがうちにあるのかっていうのを見たんだけど...
By the way, I looked to see if we had the spices for the recipe...
なんと、一つを除いて全部ありました。
and lo and behold, we had everything except for one.
まぁ4種類しかないから、まぁ3種類あったってことなんだけど...
Well, there are only four kinds, so that means we had three...
まぁ、なぜあったかと言うと、おそらくですね...
Well, as for why we had them, most likely...
3年前。3年前ぐらいに、クロたんがうちでスパイスカレーを作ってくれたことがありまして...
Three years ago, Kuro-tan made spice curry at my place...
あの、その時に、買って...
and at that time, we bought them...
で、その時に使用されて、そのまま置いてあったやつ。
and they were used then and just left there.
多分それからほとんど使ってないからあるでしょう。
They're probably there since they've hardly been used since then.
まぁ調味料ってね、大体期限大丈夫だから。少しくらい。
Well, seasonings usually last, you know. Even if it's a little past the date.
粉もんだから多分長いと思うし、大丈夫だと思いもす。はい、大丈夫。
Since they're powders, they probably last a long time, so I think it's fine.
出てこなかった時は問題だけど、爪楊枝でほじくればちょっと出てくると思うんで。
It'll be a problem if they don't come out, but a toothpick should help.
あ！やばい！これ言わない方がよかったかも。
Ah! Oh no! Maybe I shouldn't have said that.
さっき買ってきました！よいしょ。
I just bought them! There we go.
ちょっと待って、カレーへの本気度。いやでもどうなんだ、家にありました。
Wait, my dedication to the curry. But wait, we had them at home.
家にありました。本気、家にあった方が嘘じゃないし。
At home, we had them at home. It's not a lie if they were at home.
普段からスパイスを意識して生きているので...
Since I live my life being conscious of spices...
おうちにスパイスが常備されてるんですね。はい、やったー！
I keep various spices stocked at home. Yes, hooray!
証明完了. QED. オッケー、オッケー。
Proof complete. Q.E.D. Okay, okay.
待って、まだ待ってください。判断するのは早いです。
Wait, please wait a moment. It's too early to judge.
まだこれは序の口。できた時に...
This is just the beginning. When it's finished...
初めて本格スパイスカレー作る
～オリチャー有・クロワッサン有～
[Title: Making authentic spice curry for the first time
- With Original Recipe & Croissants]
...美味しければええんや。
...As long as it's delicious, it's fine.
よし、よし。じゃ、緊張しちゃうね、
やっぱ公開オーディション。
Alright, alright. I'm getting nervous,
it's a public audition after all.
違う、全く違うんですけど、公開オーディションだと思って
ちょっとドキドキしちゃうな。
No, it's completely different, but I'm a bit nervous
thinking of it as an audition.
あのね、CoCo壱さんさ、こよりほんまによく頼んでてさ。
You know, I really order from CoCo Ichibanya quite often.
Uber生活をね、ずっと、してるのね。
I've been living the Uber life for a long time.
UberのEatsにね、マジでずっとお世話になっていて、
よく頼むんよ。
I've really been relying on Uber Eats
and order from them a lot.
そんでさ、なんか「どことコラボしたいですか？」
みたいなやつをさ、
And then, I'm often asked who
I'd like to collaborate with.
ちょいちょい聞かれたりするんだけど、運営さんからの
「希望を聞きます」みたいなやつとかでも、
The staff asks for my preferences
every now and then.
もう毎年書いてて、「CoCo壱さん」って。
And every year, I've been writing down "CoCo Ichibanya."
これマジでびっくりした、
「え、CoCo壱さんやん！」ってなった。
I was so surprised, like,
"Whoa, it's really CoCo Ichibanya!"
なんやろ、って思ってたからさ。そう。
I was wondering what it was. Yeah.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
ほんとにね、なんか3日連続CoCo壱とか
食べることあったもん。
Honestly, there were times I'd eat CoCo Ichibanya
three days in a row.
無性にカレー食べたい時、
やっぱ安心安全のCoCo壱さんよね。
When I really want curry, CoCo Ichibanya
is the safe and reliable choice.
はい、ということで、みじん切りになりました！
Alright, and with that, the mincing is done!
どや！どやどやどや！
Ta-da! How's that? Look at this!
ほら！みじんになったよ。最初は不安でもね。
Look! It's minced. Even if I was unsure at first.
手も怪我していないし、みじん切りにされましたので、
これでOKということ。
My hands aren't injured, and it's minced,
so it's all good.
これ一応避難する器を用意しといたけど、別にいらなそうだな。
I prepared a bowl to move them to, but it doesn't seem necessary.
このままもう、これ以上今日切るものないんで、
一旦これラップしまって、
Since I don't have anything else to cut today,
I'll put the wrap away...
ちーちゃん、どうしたの？
ちーちゃんが急に走ってやってきた。
Chi-chan, what's wrong?
Chi-chan suddenly came running over.
ちーちゃんダメよ、玉ねぎダメだよね。
Chi-chan, no! Onions are bad for you, right?
ペットフード以外は食べさせないからアレなんだけど。
I don't let her eat anything but pet food,
so it's fine, but still.
よし。はい、ということで、おいしょおいしょ。
一旦これをどかして、
Okay. Alright, heave-ho. Let's move this aside...
もう切るものないから包丁を入れちゃって、
Nothing else to cut, so I'll put the knife away.
ふー。続きましては、これを炒めるはず。
Phew. Next up, I'm supposed to sauté this.
ぴょん。鍋に油を引きます。
Boing. I'll pour oil into the pot.
ここでオリチャー発動ですね。
Time to activate my "Ori-cha" (Original Recipe).
普通にサラダ油でやるっぽいんだけど、待って、入れて。
It seems I'm supposed to use vegetable oil...
wait, let me pour it.
やっぱりオリーブオイルの方が、女の子はおいしい嬉しいし、
But I think olive oil makes girls happier
and is more delicious.
香りがついておいしいんじゃないかなと思いますので。
The aroma should make it taste better, I think.
え？オリーブオイルやめて？何で？
Eh? "Don't use olive oil"? Why?
何で？オイルが違うくらいでは変わらんやろ。
Why? Changing the oil won't make that big a difference.
オリーブオイル香りがついてええやろ。
Olive oil adds a nice scent, doesn't it?
香りならごま油が最強やぞ。
If it's about scent, sesame oil is the strongest.
いや、ごま油も大好きだけど、ごま油はさすがに
カレーの香りとは違くね？
Well, I love sesame oil too, but it doesn't really
go with curry's aroma, does it?
大丈夫だよね。までも、多分オリーブオイルの香りなんて
感じないだろうから。
It'll be fine. Anyway, I probably won't even notice
the olive oil scent.
オリーブオイルです。中火ね。
So, olive oil it is. Medium heat.
はい、いつものね。ちょっといいオリーブオイルだと
これいつまでもフレッシュが。
The usual. With slightly better olive oil,
it stays fresh longer.
はい、にゃーどうしたの？今カレー作ってるからね。
Yes, meow, what is it? I'm making curry right now.
ちーちゃんは食べれないけどね。
You can't eat it, though, Chi-chan.
これを伸ばして中火。ま、こんなもんだろう。中火。
Spreading it out over medium heat.
That should be about right.
ね、何でCoCo壱さんに謝ってんの？
Hey, why are you guys apologizing to CoCo Ichibanya?
謝らない、え、まだ油引いただけだよちょっと。
時期尚早。
I won't apologize. Eh, I only just poured the oil.
It's premature.
謝るにはまだ早い。謝る気もない。
It's too early to apologize. I have no intention
of apologizing anyway.
で、熱されたら、あったかくなってきた。
And once it's heated... it's getting warm.
ちーちゃんどうしたの？玉ねぎを、一旦軽く、軽くやります。
Chi-chan, what's wrong? I'll lightly, lightly
sauté the onions.
おお、いい音！逃げた。ちーちゃんが逃げました。
Ooh, great sound! She ran away.
Chi-chan ran away.
軽く炒めます。
Lightly frying them.
ちょっと待って、これ多分弱？弱かなちょっとうるさいからね。
弱で。
Wait, maybe low heat? It's a bit loud, so I'll go
with low heat.
よいしょ... 美味しくなれー。
Heave-ho... Turn out delicious.
飴色になるまで炒めるんだよね、ホントはね。
Normally, you're supposed to sauté them
until they're caramelized.
でも今日はオリチャーだから、そこまでしなくてもいいかなって。
But since this is my original recipe today,
maybe I don't need to go that far.
いい香りしてきたー！玉ねぎの甘い香りが。
It's starting to smell great! That sweet aroma of onions.
これをしっかり炒めることでコクが出るんだよね。
Sautéing them well adds depth to the flavor.
カレー作りって、この玉ねぎを炒める時間が
一番大事だったりするよね。
In curry making, this time spent sautéing the onions
might be the most important part.
…けて、えー…
...and, uh...
軽く炒めて、
Stir-fry it lightly,
で、水大さじ2を入れて…
And then add two tablespoons of water...
あぁーっ！！
Aaah!!
水が跳ね散らかしました。
The water splashed everywhere.
まず大さじ1、
First, one tablespoon,
2。はい、水大さじ2を入れて、
Two. Okay, add two tablespoons of water,
ちょ、あの大さじにさ、直で水蛇口から入れたら、
Hey, when I put the water directly from the tap into the spoon,
なんかびちょびちょになったけど、びちょびちょになったの見えないわ。
it got all soggy, but you can't see the sogginess.
え、なんか静かになっちゃった。
Eh, it's gotten quiet suddenly.
静かになっちゃったんだけど、
It's gotten quiet, though.
これでね、えっと、蒸すらしい。
With this, well, apparently you're supposed to steam it.
この後も。
Even after this.
蓋をして、
Put the lid on,
蓋ね、反射が怖いから、ちょっと遠ざかりながら蓋をして、
I'm scared of the reflection on the lid, so I'll stay back while putting it on.
えー、2、3分ほど蒸します。
And steam it for about two or three minutes.
これ蒸してると、玉ねぎが…あの、なんか透明になるらしい。
Apparently, while steaming, the onions... will become transparent.
閉まりきってないわ。
It's not closed all the way.
え、水入れるの早い？
Eh, was I too early to add water?
いやいやいや、ここで焦げちゃいかんから、
No no no, we don't want it to burn here,
このタイミングだと思うんですけどね。
so I think this is the right timing.
2、3分…今21分だから、23分までにしようかな。
Two or three minutes... it's 21 minutes now, so let's go until 23.
蒸したものがこちらです、2分ぐらい待てや！
Here's the steamed version—wait for two minutes!
え、今日はでもね、あのお肉、鶏肉を入れるんだけど、鶏肉の下処理はしてある。
But today, I'm adding meat, chicken, and I've already prepped it.
無水カレーにしよう、今からやめて。次作るわ、じゃあ今回成功して。
Let's make waterless curry—stop it. I'll make it next time if this one succeeds.
成功した暁には、無水カレーの日がやってくる可能性もある。
There's a chance a day for waterless curry will come if this succeeds.
今日は有水カレーです。
Today is 'water-added' curry.
違うんだって、飴色になるまで炒めるって書いてないから。
No, listen, it doesn't say to fry until caramel-colored.
書いてないから、これで合ってるんですって。
It doesn't say that, so this is correct.
え、これ待って、成功するか否かみたいなの聞く？
Wait, should I ask if it'll succeed or not?
えっと、アンケート…
Um, a poll...
アンケートを開始。
Starting the poll.
「初めてのスパイスカレー」、スパイスから作るカレー、成功する？
[Poll: 'First Spice Curry' - Curry from spices, will it succeed?]
「はい、成功する」。これでいい？
Option A: 'Yes, it will.' Is this okay?
「はい」と「成功する」だけでいい？ダメか…
Is just 'Yes' and 'It will succeed' enough? No...
失敗するかも。
Option B: 'Maybe fail.'
いやでも、ちゃんと「失敗するかも」と「成功する」に変えましたけど、
I properly changed it to 'might fail' and 'will succeed,' though.
失敗したカレーをこよりは食べたことがあるから、自分でジャッジできる。
Since Koyori has eaten failed curry before, I can judge it myself.
そこは正直にジャッジします、うん。
I'll judge it honestly, yeah.
あの、今日ポストもしたんだけど、学生の頃…
I posted about it today, but back when I was a student...
あ、待って、23分なった。
Oh wait, it's been 23 minutes.
ぱっ。あ、暑そー。
Pop! Ah, looks hot.
学生の頃ですね、あの、飯盒炊爨みたいなやつで作った、
When I was a student, I made it with something like a mess kit,
え、なんか透明っぽくない？！
Eh, doesn't it look transparent?!
カレーがね、水っぽくてびちゃびちゃになって、とっても…
the curry turned out watery and soggy, and it was...
ま、水っぽさがね、全然スープカレーにもなりきれなくて、
well, the wateriness didn't even make it a soup curry,
味薄くてね、めちゃくちゃ不味かったっていう経験があって。
it was bland and tasted awful—I have that experience.
え、でもこのしなしな、いい感じだよね？いい感じ、いい感じ。
Eh, but this wilted look is good, right? Good, good.
ね、これ水分飛ばしつつ透き通るまで炒めるんで、
Right, so I'll fry it until transparent while letting the moisture evaporate,
もうちょっとかな？まだ透き通ってないもんね。
maybe a little more? It's not transparent yet.
透き通るかな？でも水分は飛んでそう。いや、そんな飛んでないか。
Will it get clear? The moisture seems gone... or not really.
まだびちょっとしてるか。いや、水は多くない、多くない。
Is it still soggy? No, it's not too much water.
ここかな？ここから炒める。まだ炒める。
Maybe this is it? I'll fry it from here. Still frying.
美味そう…もう。
Looks delicious... already.
玉ねぎ入ってるだけで栄養いいからね。美味しいからね。
Just having onions makes it nutritious. Because it's tasty.
いいんじゃない、いいんじゃない。いい感じに炒まってるんじゃない？
Isn't this good? Isn't it frying up nicely?
あ、透けてる！透けて、ほら見て見て透けてる！スケルトン！
Ah, it's clear! It's transparent, look! It's skeleton!
だけどこれちゃんと透けるのかなって結構ね、心配してたんだけど
But I was actually quite worried about whether these would really turn translucent...
行けそうな気がする
...but I think it's gonna work out.
いや、飴色にはしない
No, I'm not going for "amber" onions.
今日はね、飴色玉ねぎじゃないっぽい
Looks like today's not for amber onions.
ま、煮込むしね
Well, I'm going to simmer them anyway.
飴色じゃない玉ねぎ
Non-amber onions.
スケルトン玉ねぎにします、今日は
I'll make them "skeleton" (translucent) onions today.
よいしょ
There we go.
いいんじゃない？
Looking good, right?
ちょっと薄めにこうやって敷いて、透けてるかどうかを
I'll spread them out a bit thin like this and see if they're translucent...
見えるようにしつつ、次のものを用意しとこうかな
...while keeping an eye on that, and I'll get the next things ready.
えー、にんにく、生姜、トマトピューレ
Um, garlic, ginger, tomato puree.
えー、にんにく、生姜はね、これいつもあの、こよりが飲んでる...
Um, garlic, and for ginger... it's the ginger I always put in...
蜂蜜生姜紅茶に入れてる生姜ね
...the honey ginger tea I drink.
と、トマトピューレ。は買ってきた。よし
And tomato puree. I bought some. Alright.
これトマトピューレがさ、100gなんだけどさ
This tomato puree, it's 100g...
200gしか売ってなくて、この残った100gをどうすればいいんだろう...
...but they only sold 200g packs. I'm wondering what to do with the remaining 100g...
っていうのに悩んでるのと、どうやって100gを計ればいいのかが分からなくて
...and I don't know how I should measure out 100g.
こよりさ、昔さ、あの、ケーキ作りしたじゃん
You know, I once made a cake a while back.
その時に...
At that time...
あ、ここかも！
Oh, it might be here!
あ、ないわ
Oh, never mind.
そう、ケーキ作りの時に絶対に、あの、買ったはずなの
Yeah, I'm sure I must have bought...
計量器を！
...a scale!
ないんだよねー
I can't find it though.
どこ...
Where...
どこ行ったんだろうなー、マジで
Where could it have gone, seriously?
あ！あれだ！あった！ちょっと待って、あった！
Ah! That's it! I found it! Wait a sec, I found it!
見つけた！
I found it!
よしじゃあ、最初の仕込みの時のヨーグルトもこれで計れたんだ
Alright then, I could have measured the yogurt for the initial prep with this too.
よいしょよいしょ
There we go, there we go.
ありましたわ
I have it!
じゃあ、よいしょ。測って...
Now then, let's see. Measuring...
やべぇ、椅子に付いてる猫の毛がめっちゃ、めっちゃ手に移った。待って
Oh no, the cat hair from my chair is getting all over my hands. Wait.
玉ねぎ...あ、やばい！飴色になっちゃう！
The onions... Oh no! They're turning amber!
ちょっと待って、ちょっと、ちょっと弱火にしよ
Hold on, I'll turn the heat down a bit.
あ！あ！
Ah! Ah!
なんで透明になる前に飴色になるの？どうして？
Why are they turning amber before becoming transparent? Why?
で、えー...
And, uh...
電池あるかなー
I wonder if it has batteries.
あ、あったあったあった。まあその時しか使ってないからそりゃなくなってないよね。よし
Oh, found some. Well, I only used it that one time, so they shouldn't be dead. Alright.
これね、タニタさんのやつね
This one, it's the Tanita one.
で、えー、入りして
And, uh, turn it on...
で、この、お米の計量カップに100g計ると
Then, I'll measure 100g in this rice measuring cup.
あー！
Ah!
漏れ出してくるー
It's leaking out!
やばいやばい
This is bad, this is bad.
えっと、17gだから117まで
Um, it's 17g, so I'll go up to 117.
あ！
Ah!
蓋のとこに付いちゃった
It got on the lid.
あ、まあ110...あーあー、すごいボトボト。ボトボト落ちてます
Ah, well 110... Oh man, it's dripping everywhere. It's dripping down.
やばい
Oh no.
あ、待って。ちょ、ちょっと切っとこ。やばい、焦げ始めた、焦げ始めた！
Oh, wait. Let me turn it off for a second. Oh no, it's starting to burn, it's burning!
なんか現場みたいになっちゃった
It's like a crime scene in here.
よいしょ、これ拭いて
There, wipe this off.
で、電池もったいないから切りして、で、これは一旦
And, turning it off so I don't waste the batteries, and I'll put this aside for now.
こっちに置いて。そしたらですね
Place it here. And then...
やばい、焦げ始めている。ま、でも大丈夫、飴色って言うからね
Oh no, it's starting to burn. Well, but it's okay, I'll just call it "amber".
えっと、にんにくと生姜を
Um, garlic and ginger...
本当は本物をって書いてあるけど
The recipe says fresh ones, but...
ま、おろしてるやつで。どれぐらいか分かんない、一欠片ぐらい
...well, I'll use the grated ones. I don't know how much, about one clove's worth.
にんにく
Garlic.
生姜。ちょ、やばい。蜂蜜生姜紅茶よう飲んでるから、ちょ、生姜がほぼほぼない
Ginger. Oh, wait. I drink honey ginger tea so often that there's almost no ginger left.
よいしょ、これ無くなったら買いに行かんと。これ入れるだけでね、なんかあの...
There, I'll have to go buy some when I'm out. Just adding this, you know...
紅茶がすごいレベルが上がったみたいな風になるからおすすめです。市販品で行けるからね
...it makes the tea feel like it's leveled up, so I recommend it. You can just use store-bought stuff.
で、これとトマトピューレを足す
Now, add this and the tomato puree.
2g多かった分、これ残る分でちょうどいいか。えー、ちょ、待って
Since it was 2g too much, maybe it'll balance out with what stays in the cup. Wait...
そう、これトマトピューレ入れるタイプだから
Yeah, this is the type where you add tomato puree.
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
よし
Alright.
そしたらこれを混ぜます
Then, I'll mix this.
よいしょ、よいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
トマトが入ると急にそれっぽくなるね
It suddenly looks more like it once the tomato is in.
いいんじゃない？
Looking good, right?
そしたらですね、ここに...
Then, here...
あ、鶏肉ね
Oh, the chicken.
鶏肉を投入します！
I'll put in the chicken!
さっき漬けといた鶏肉
The chicken I marinated earlier.
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
これを、タレごと
This, along with the sauce.
投入
Going in.
よいしょ、よいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
よし
Alright.
そしたらまた混ぜて
Then mix again,
鶏肉に、この、トマトと玉ねぎを絡めていく
...and coat the chicken with this tomato and onion mixture.
よいしょ、よいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
あ、いい匂い！めっちゃいい匂いする
Ah, what a great smell! It smells so good.
スパイスのいい匂い
The nice smell of spices.
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
鶏肉がね、結構大きいから
The chicken pieces are quite big,
ちゃんとね、火を通さないとね
...so I have to make sure they're cooked through.
よいしょ、よいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
そしたらですね、ここにスパイスを入れていくよ
And then, I'll add the spices here.
スパイスはですね...
The spices are...
クミン、コリアンダー、ターメリック
Cumin, coriander, and turmeric.
これを小さじ1ずつ
One teaspoon of each.
まずはターメリック
First, turmeric.
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
ターメリック、投入
Turmeric, going in.
コリアンダー
Coriander.
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
コリアンダー、投入
Coriander, going in.
クミン
Cumin.
初めて本格スパイスカレー作る～オリチャー有・クロワッサン有～
[Title: Making authentic spice curry for the first time ~With my original recipe and croissants~]
こよりちゃん辛いの苦手だけど ちょうどいいかなと思って
Koyori is bad with spicy food, but I thought this might be just right.
こよりちゃん辛いの苦手だけど ちょうどいいかなという所存
I feel like it'll be just right despite being bad with spicy food.
はい 水に浸けといて... こういうところ A型ね
Okay, soaking it in water... That's a "Type A" trait.
A型出ちゃった
The Type A in me is showing.
しっかりね あの... 器に水をすぐ張るやつね
Gotta make sure... to fill the bowl with water right away.
おお! 何かうまそうな気がする
Ooh! I have a feeling this is gonna be delicious.
作ってるのナポリタンやったかな?
Wait, was I making Napolitan?
でもナポリタンはケチャップもんね
But Napolitan uses ketchup, doesn't it?
これトマト... あ!
This is tomato... Oh!
あ すごい 完熟トマトの香りする
Wow, it smells like ripe tomatoes.
めっちゃ香りするなあ
It really has a strong aroma.
これ白い服に飛びそうだな
This looks like it'll splatter on my white clothes.
気をつけよう
Better be careful.
で これを混ぜつつ全体に
And now, mixing this in...
行ったんだろうか あの生姜とニンニクの塊は
...did those chunks of ginger and garlic blend in?
エプロンつけてへんの? ほら エプロンも白やからさ
Not wearing an apron? See, my apron is white too.
エプロンが赤く染まっちゃいそうじゃない これ メイド服なのに
My apron might get stained red, even though it's a maid outfit.
メイド服汚れちゃうとさ 寂しいじゃん
It'd be sad if my maid outfit got dirty.
さて 炒めてます
Well, I'm sautéing it.
お! ここでスパイスが出てきますよ もう
Oh! The spices are coming out now!
ドキドキ... あくかな?
How exciting... I wonder if it'll open?
えー まず これ炒めてられてるのかな?
Uh, first... is this being sautéed properly?
ここでいいのかちょっと分かんないけど
I'm not sure if this is the right timing, but...
ちょっと上げて...
Turning up the heat a bit...
まず まあこれは入るよねという
First, well, this has to go in...
クミン
Cumin
あ 大丈夫そう 大丈夫そう
Ah, it seems okay, seems okay.
え 小さじ1ですね
Uh, one teaspoon.
おお 結構入る
Ooh, quite a lot.
全然出てこない
It's not coming out at all.
あ やばい ここでやると水蒸気で固まりそうだから
Oh no, if I do it here, the steam might make it clump up.
やばい 出てこねえ
Oh shoot, it's not coming out.
トントン... あ! クミンが舞ってる
Tap, tap... Oh! The cumin is flying everywhere.
やばい 小さじ出すのも大変なんだけど
Geez, even getting a teaspoon out is a struggle.
あ すごい香り!
Ah, what a great smell!
手袋がクミンの香りでいっぱいになりそうです
My gloves are gonna reek of cumin.
これ カード開封の時とか...
This is like when I'm opening cards...
あーー!!
AAUGH!!
振ったら... あの ちゃんと小さじかなと思って振ったら...
I was shaking it to see if it was a full teaspoon, and...
めっちゃこぼしちゃった
I spilled so much.
これぐらいかな?
Is this about right?
うん まあこんなもんでしょう
Yeah, I guess this will do.
ぽい!
Plop!
はーい クミン!
Okay, cumin!
はい クミン入りましーた
Okay, the cumin has been added.
やばい 焦げる 焦げる やばい
Oh no, it's burning! It's burning! This is bad!
あ あ やばい やばいかも
Ah, ah, this might be bad!
待って これ火止めたほうがいい?
Wait, should I turn off the heat?
いや まだ焦げてない
No, it's not burnt yet.
まだ大丈夫そう ちょっと待って
It seems okay still. Wait a sec.
一回保温... 保温機能とかないわ あるわ
Let me "keep warm"... I don't have that... oh, wait, I do.
一回切って...
Let me turn it off for a bit...
え 次コリアンダー
Uh, next is coriander.
お前ら コリアンダーって何だか知ってます?
Do you guys know what coriander is?
そうなの コリアンダーってパクチーのことなんだよ
That's right, coriander is actually cilantro.
でもさ このスパイスの形状になってると あんまりパクチーパクチーした香りがしなくて
But you know, in this spice form, it doesn't really smell like cilantro.
こより パクチー大好き女なんで
I'm a girl who loves cilantro, so...
コリアンダーも好きなんだけど...
I like coriander too, but...
茶色いんだね
It's brown, huh?
コリアンダーって緑色だと思ってた パクチーだから
I thought coriander would be green since it's cilantro.
あと最後にパセリをかけるんだけど パセリあったかな? 色味のために
Also, I'll add parsley at the end. Did I have any? For the color.
よし こんなもんか
Okay, is this enough?
ちょっと少ないか こんなもんか
Maybe a bit more. I guess this will do.
はい ということで こちらコリアンダーです
Okay, so this is the coriander.
ポン!
Plop!
かけまして...
Sprinkled it in...
よし
Good.
まあでもそんなね パクチー苦手な人がパクチー! ってなるほどのパクチー臭は やっぱコリアンダーになっちゃうとしないね
But you know, once it becomes coriander spice, it doesn't have that strong cilantro smell that makes people who hate it go "Cilantro!"
次は ターメリック
Next is turmeric.
ターメリック
Turmeric
ハイ、というわけで、ウコンですね。
Okay, so here is the turmeric.
コリアンダーはパクチーの種だよ。え、そうなの？
Coriander is cilantro seeds? Oh, is that so?
え、じゃあ全然違うやん。葉っぱとは違うやん。
Wait, then it's totally different. It's different from the leaves.
おおー、カレーの色だ！
Ooh! It's the color of curry!
ターメリックがカレーとしてデカイもんね。
Turmeric is a big part of what makes it curry.
あ、これまずい。小さじ1/2だった。
Oh, this is bad. It was supposed to be 1/2 tsp.
ノリで小さじ1計ってたけど、まあちょうど、ちょうど1/2ぐらいだよね。
I measured a full teaspoon on a whim, but it's about half now, right?
はい。
Yes.
ウコン、ウコンの力。ターメリック入れます。
Turmeric, the power of turmeric. In it goes.
で、この後に入れるのがチリパウダーなんだけど、
And what we add after this is chili powder,
チリパウダーなくて、しかもこよちゃん辛いの苦手だから、
but I don't have any, and I'm not good with spicy food anyway,
チリパウダーじゃない方がいいなって思って、
so I thought it would be better to use something else.
何を入れようかなって思ってるんですけど、
I'm wondering what I should use instead,
オリチャー発動で、何かいいのあるかな？ 花椒とかどう？
activating the Original Recipe... is there anything good? How about Szechuan pepper?
花椒。チリっぽくない？
Szechuan pepper. Doesn't that seem a bit like chili?
パプリカでええやん。さっきに聞きたかったな。パプリカのパウダーはうちにないかな？
Paprika would've been fine. I wish I'd asked sooner. Do I have paprika powder?
花椒は違う？
Szechuan pepper is no good?
はい、えーじゃあ、ちょっと待ってね。
Okay, well, give me a moment.
ローズマリー、うーん。
Rosemary... hmm.
粗挽き胡椒、ホワイトペッパー。
Coarsely ground pepper, white pepper.
ホワイトペッパーなら、チリパウダーの代わりになるんじゃない？
If it's white pepper, maybe it can be a substitute for chili powder?
アンケート変えていい？ いやいやいや、いけるから。
Can I change the poll? No, no, it's fine.
チリソースはあるんだけどな。豆板醤は違うし。
I have chili sauce, though. Doubanjiang is different too.
コンソメとかもあるけど。
I also have things like consomme.
で、マヨネーズを入れたいわけ。
But I want to add mayonnaise.
から、したな、チリパウダー小さじ1/2の代わりに、
So, instead of 1/2 tsp of chili powder,
ホワイトペッパーを少々。
I'll add a bit of white pepper.
少々ね。と、隠し味にマヨネーズ。
Just a bit. And mayonnaise as a secret ingredient.
マヨネーズを入れるのはコクになるので、
Adding mayonnaise adds richness,
普通にね、カレーに隠し味マヨネーズはあるんで、
it's actually a common secret ingredient for curry,
隠し味だから、
and since it's a secret ingredient...
愛よね。愛を注入でございます。
It's love. Injecting it with love.
マイルドになってね、美味しいの。コクも出ますでしょう。
It becomes mild and delicious. It should add richness too.
はい。ということで、これちょっとマヨネーズ少ないから、
Okay. That said, this is a bit too little mayonnaise,
もっと入れないと意味がないかな、もしかして。
maybe it won't even matter unless I add more.
愛3倍がけね。
Triple the love!
3回入れた、3回。
I added it three times, three times!
ということで、入れることができましたので、
And so, now that I've added it,
ちょっと待って、スマホを見て。
Wait a second, let me check my phone.
からの、ここで下仕込みをしてあった子が来ます。
And now, the one I've been prepping comes in.
これね、マヨネーズ入れてて大丈夫な理由が実はここにあって、
The reason why it's okay to add mayonnaise is actually right here,
この下仕込みがね、結構大事なところなんですよ。なんと、
this preparation is a very important part. And here it is!
ジャジャーン！ご覧ください。
Ta-da! Take a look at this.
これどうですか？トマトピューレが干からびてる、大丈夫、この後水入れるから大丈夫。
How's this? The tomato puree is dried out, but it's okay. I'll add water later.
今回スープカレーだからね。はい、こちらはですね、なんと、
Since it's soup curry this time. Now, this is actually...
鶏肉をヨーグルト、無糖ヨーグルトとちょっと塩で漬けておいたものです。
chicken marinated in unsweetened yogurt and a bit of salt.
で、このヨーグルトそのまま入れるということなので、混ぜてからがいいか。
And since I'm adding the yogurt as is... maybe I should mix it first.
干からびてる！干からび始めている！危険、危険。
It's drying out! It's starting to dry out! Danger, danger.
まあ、水入れるからね、多分大丈夫。
Well, I'm adding water, so it should be fine.
なんなんこれ、こんなにねちょねちょしてたっけ。
What is this? Was it always this sticky?
あ、でもね、香りはもう...
Ah, but the smell is already...
ねぇこれさ、今このまま食べたら無水カレーなんじゃない？
Hey, if I were to eat this as it is now,
wouldn't it be waterless curry?
ねばねばしてる。無水カレーってこんな感じ？
It's sticky. Is waterless curry like this?
あ、待って、マヨネーズで色がなんか、マイルドになってる。可愛い。
Oh, wait, the mayonnaise makes the color look...
mild. Cute.
はい、こうして。でー、えー...
Okay, like this. And, um...
この、
This...
ヨーグルトと入れる...
Add it with the yogurt...
はい、ヨーグルトと、この鶏肉を入れまして。
Okay, I've added the yogurt and this chicken.
元気がないな。
It doesn't seem to have much life.
混ぜ合わせる。
Now to mix it together.
鶏肉は美味しそう。まだ生だよ。
The chicken looks delicious.
It's still raw, though.
混ぜ合わせて、なんか本格感出てきてない？
After mixing it, doesn't it look kind of authentic?
この色、色味。途中で白が混ざるのが本格感出てくるよね。
This color, the tint. Adding white in the middle
makes it look authentic, doesn't it?
なんかバターチキンカレーみたいな色になってる。
It looks like the color of butter chicken curry.
ちなみにね、チキンはなんか大きめって書いてあったから、大きめに切ってあるやつを買ってきました。
By the way, it said large pieces, so I bought
chicken that was already cut into big chunks.
で、えっと、皮を取るって書いてあったんだけど、それを見忘れたんで、皮はちょっと付いたままなんですけど。
And, um, it said to remove the skin, but I missed
that, so some of the skin is still on.
もこちゃん皮取らない派なんで、まあ大丈夫かなーと。
But Moko-chan is in the 'don't remove the skin'
camp, so I think it's fine.
はい混ぜ合わせ終わったな。美味しくなりそうだね。ね？
Okay, I've finished mixing it.
It looks like it'll be delicious, right?
したら水入れます。200cc。
Now I'll add water. 200cc.
えー、前回も活躍したプロテインシェイカーので、200ccを計る。
Measuring out 200cc with the protein shaker
that was so useful last time.
ああ！
Ah!
大丈夫。
I'm okay.
えーっと、鍋の蓋が落ちましたと。
Um, the pot lid just fell.
200cc、これくらいかな。
200cc, is it about this much?
はいプロテインシェイカーで200cc水を入っ、入れます！
Okay, adding 200cc of water with the protein shaker!
おー、元気なくなった。
Oh, the sizzling stopped.
ちょっと、あの、今場所がさ、狭くてさ。あの、すごい不安定なとこに蓋置いといたから、そのせいで蓋が落ちた。
It's a bit cramped here right now... I put the lid
in a very unstable spot, and that's why it fell.
え、なんかビチョビチョじゃない？
Wait, isn't it kind of watery?
こんなもんなのかな。スープカレーか？
Is it supposed to be like this? Is it soup curry?
で、水を加えて煮立っ、煮立たせる。じゃあちょっと、あれさせるか。強火にして。
Then, I add water and let it come to a boil.
I'll turn it up to high heat.
ぷくぷくぷくぷく。
Bloop, bloop, bloop, bloop.
ちょっと、横にこびり付いてるのをこうやってやって。
Let's scrape off the bits stuck to the sides
like this.
え、でもなんか色合いバターチキンカレーだね。
But the color really does look like
butter chicken curry.
で、生肉だとやばいんで、鶏肉をしっかり中につけて。
And it would be bad if the meat is raw,
so make sure the chicken is submerged.
スパイスがダマになってそう。え、そうかな？そんなことない気がする。ヨーグルトと混ぜ合わせたから。
The spices might be clumpy. You think so?
I don't think so, since I mixed it with yogurt.
辛いかな？もう辛い要素ないよね。
I wonder if it's spicy. There are no spicy
ingredients left, right?
ターメリックって辛い？
Is turmeric spicy?
クミンも香りだし。
Cumin is for the aroma too.
しっかり入れて。
Make sure it's all in there.
でー、
And...
煮立たせる。あ、煮立っ、煮立ってきた。
Let it boil. Oh, it's starting to boil.
煮立ってきた煮立ってきた。
It's boiling, it's boiling.
これ煮立ってる？
Is this boiling?
辛い要素入ってなくない？そうだよね。チリ、チリペッパー入れなければ辛くない説、あると思います。
There aren't any spicy ingredients, right? I think the
theory that it's not spicy without chili holds true.
このヘラから落として...
Scraping it off this spatula...
【料理／カメラ有】はじめての本格スパイスカレー作る～オリチャー有・クロワッサン有～
[Title: First Time Making Authentic Spice Curry - With Original Chart & Croissants]
で、煮立ってきたから、え、まだこれ煮立ってないの？
Now that it's boiling... wait, is it not boiling yet?
煮立ってない？グツグツいっとるよ。
Not boiling? It's bubbling away.
でもなんかアクの出方がさ、すごいちょっとカレー本格カレー感あるすでに。
But the way the foam is coming out...
すごいちょっとカレー本格カレー感あるすでに。
it already feels like an authentic curry.
煮立ってるよね。煮立ってきたら、
It is boiling. Once it starts boiling,
えっと、弱めの中火... お、お...
then set it to a low-medium heat...
これぐらいかな？
About this much?
弱めの中火で蓋をして...
On low-medium heat, I'll put the lid on...
煮込ませます。これを、え、10分から12分ほど煮込むんね。
And let it simmer. I'll let this simmer for about 10 to 12 minutes.
洗い物していい？その隙に。
Can I do the dishes while I wait?
11分にしとこう。いやでもそこはさ、
I'll set it to 11 minutes. Actually, wait...
生だと怖いから12分にしとこうかな。
I'm scared of it being raw, so let's go with 12 minutes.
みんなとおしゃべりしながら洗い物するわ。
I'll do the dishes while chatting with everyone.
こよさ、片付けをするのがとにかく嫌いでさ。
I really hate tidying up.
だから、この、食べ終わった後ってもう癒やされた時間じゃん？
Because, you know, after eating is supposed to be relaxing time.
癒やされた時間に片付けるのがほんまに嫌で。
I really hate having to clean up during that relaxing time.
わっ！いろんなものが落ちますけど、
Whoops! Things are falling over...
トマトピューレを冷蔵庫に入れて、落ちたものを拾って...
Putting the tomato puree in the fridge, picking up the fallen things...
おもちゃボックスが落ちた。
The toy box fell.
からさ、この、食べる前に片付けしちゃいたい派なのだ。
So, I'm the type who wants to finish tidying up before eating.
洗い物しよう。
Let's do the dishes.
よく落としますな。
I'm dropping things a lot.
今日はなぜこんなに物が落ちるのか自分でもわかりません。
I don't even know why things are falling so much today.
やばい、粉が待ってるんですけど洗い場に。
Oh no, there's flour waiting for me at the sink.
時短にもなる。こういう暇な時に洗い物をしてしまうわけ。
It's a time-saver too. Doing the dishes during down moments like this.
家庭的でしょ？
Doesn't that look domestic?
こよちゃんの家庭的なところ見えちゃった。
You're seeing Koyo-chan's domestic side.
これ食べ終わる頃には乾いてるから、このまま置いとけば。
By the time I'm done eating, these will be dry if I just leave them here.
これ生肉入ってたやつは気をつけつつね、洗わないとね。
I have to be careful when washing the ones that had raw meat in them.
そうだね、えらい。
That's right, good job.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
皿割りそう？大丈夫。ガラスのものは一切表に出てないから大丈夫。
Break a plate? It's fine. None of the glass items are out, so it's okay.
でもあのマヨネーズがどれぐらいの隠し味になるか楽しみだな。
But I'm looking forward to seeing how much of a secret ingredient that mayonnaise becomes.
あ、そう、クロワッサンカレー？そうなんです。
Oh right, Croissant Curry? That's right.
書いといたんだった、そういえば。「クロワッサンあり」って。
Come to think of it, I did write that croissants are included.
あのさ、カレーを作ろうと思ってた上に、こよりは今日ポケモンのことを考えてて、
I was planning to make curry, and on top of that, I was thinking about Pokemon today...
あ、そういえばZ-Aのクロワッサンカレー、なんやかんや見た目すごいけど美味しそうって
Oh, I remembered talking with everyone about how the Croissant Curry in Z-A...
美味しそうってみんなと話してたなと思いまして。
looks intense but somehow delicious.
盛り付けをあんな感じにできたらいいなと思い、クロワッサンも買ってきました。
I thought it'd be cool if I could plate it like that, so I bought some croissants.
でもさ、クロワッサンカレーは普通に美味しいと思うんだ。
But you know, I think Croissant Curry would actually be tasty.
クロワッサンって甘い味付いてないし、
Croissants aren't sweetened,
あのサクサク感が普通にカレーにマッチして美味しそうじゃない？
and wouldn't that flaky texture match the curry and be delicious?
こよ特製のクロワッサンカレー。うちお祝いじゃないけど。
Koyo's special Croissant Curry. Not that it's a celebration.
ナンの代わりにクロワッサン。
Croissants instead of naan.
確かにね、ナンで食べるし、ナンも油っぽいから結構。
True, people eat with naan, and naan is also quite oily.
サクサク感がなくなるやろがい。
But the flakiness will be gone!
だから、あの、横に添える時にあまり汁に浸からないようにして、
That's why, when I serve them on the side, I'll try not to let them soak in the sauce...
ちょいちょい付けながら食べるのが美味しいと思うんだよね。
I think dipping them bit by bit while eating will be delicious.
ちーちゃーん
Chi-chaaan.
今日のご飯は、あんまり興味ない香りしてます？
Does today's meal have a scent
you're not very interested in?
ちーちゃんいなくなっちゃった。
Chi-chan is gone.
足元に来て遊んでくれるかなって思ってたのにー。
I thought you'd come to my feet and play with me...
さて。
Well then.
待って、何分からやった？
Wait, what minute did I start from?
45分？
45 minutes?
よく物を落とすから逃げた？
She ran away because I drop things often?
えー、確かに。その説はあるかも。
Eh, definitely. That might be a possibility.
スパイスあんまり好きじゃないかな。
Maybe she doesn't like spices much.
スパイスの香りってそうなのかな。
I wonder if that's how spice scents are.
物焼いてるとね、ちーちゃん絶対足元来るんだけど。
When I'm grilling something,
Chi-chan definitely comes to my feet.
まあ、こよりは普段物を焼かないので。
Well, since Koyori doesn't usually grill things...
ママお手（おて）がうちに来てくれて、お肉焼いてるとき。
When Mama-te comes to our house and grills meat...
もう絶対足元でニャーニャーニャーニャー言ってる。
she's absolutely at her feet going
"meow meow meow meow."
45分っていうのを見た気がするから。
I think I saw it was 45 minutes.
とりあえず57分まで待ちかな。
For now, I guess I'll wait until 57 minutes.
じゃあ、ちょっとクロワッサンの準備とかしとこうかな。
Then, I'll prepare the croissants a bit.
やっぱ、あのあれを作るには...
After all, to make that thing...
待って、お米も用意するか。
Wait, let's prepare the rice too.
あの真ん中って多分さ、塔（とう）だよね。
That middle part is probably a tower, right?
お米...よいしょ。
Rice... there we go.
サトウのごはん...
Sato no Gohan (pre-packaged rice)...
2分チンして。
Microwave it for 2 minutes.
クロワッサン。
Croissants.
今からご飯炊くの？安心してください。
Cooking rice now? Don't worry.
うちはサトウのごはんが完備されてるんで。
We're fully equipped with Sato no Gohan.
こよいち楽しみ。
Looking forward to Koyoi-chi.
あ、こよいちにすればよかった、タイトル。
Ah, I should've made the title "Koyoi-chi."
待って、このクロワッサンちょっと甘そうなんだけど。
Wait, these croissants look a bit sweet.
え、甘い系クロワッサンなんだけど。
Eh, they're the sweet kind of croissants.
しかもさ、囲もうと思って今置いたんだけど。
And I just placed them to surround it...
真ん中にもう寄ってきてるっていうね。
but they're already moving towards the middle.
どこに置くんだろう。
I wonder where I should put them.
真ん中にご飯の塔を置いて。
Put the rice tower in the middle.
ていっ。
There!
甘い奴だった。よく見てなかった。
They were sweet ones. I didn't look closely.
いっぱい入ってるやつ買ってきたんだけど。
I bought a pack with many in it.
バター入ってそう。までもね、バターチキンカレーも存在するから。
Seems like they have butter. But well,
butter chicken curry exists too.
これ、もう見た目バターチキンカレーの色してたし。
This looks like the color
of butter chicken curry anyway.
ま、ちょうどいいんじゃないかな。
Well, maybe it's just right.
ちーちゃん！
Chi-chan!
あった！ちーちゃんお気に入りのとこにいたの！
There! She was in her favorite spot!
ちーちゃんお気に入りのね、あの...
Chi-chan's favorite, that...
猫様専用空気清浄機の上の寝れるところがずっとお気に入りで。
She's always loved the sleeping spot on top
of the air purifier for cats.
いつ見てもそこにいるんだけど。
Whenever I look, she's there.
そこにいました。寛いでました。
She was there. She was relaxing.
ニャン聞こえた？
Did you hear the meow?
いつもの場所にいた。
She was in her usual spot.
あと4分くらい。
About 4 more minutes.
ちーちゃん！
Chi-chan!
寛いでるから。
She's relaxing.
あ、サトウのごはんできた。
Ah, the Sato no Gohan is done.
ちょ、ごめんごめんごめん！すごい嫌がってる！
Hey, sorry sorry sorry! She really hates it!
なんで？こんなに嫌がることなかなかないんだけど。
Why? She rarely hates it this much.
これ、あれか？もしかして手袋してるからこよりちゃんだってわかんなかったかな。
Is it because I'm wearing gloves she didn't
realize it's Koyori-chan?
やばい、手袋にすごい毛がついた！
Oh no, so much hair got on the gloves!
やばい。ちょっと待って。
Oh no. Wait a second.
どうしよう。
What should I do?
毛が...
The hair...
スパイス、スパイスの香りそんなに嫌なの？
Spice, do you hate the smell of spices that much?
ごめん。それはごめん。本当にごめん。悪るいと思ってる。
Sorry. I'm sorry for that. Truly sorry.
I know it's bad.
ごめんね。
Sorry...
だから近づいてこなかったのか。
Is that why you didn't come near?
スパイス嫌いなの、猫って。
Do cats hate spices?
え、でもこよりじゃあ今日ダメじゃん。一生ちーに愛されないじゃん。
Eh, then Koyori is no good today.
I won't be loved by Chi-chan forever.
クミンの香りが嫌なんだ。
She hates the smell of cumin.
隠れちゃった。
She hid.
よいしょ。ちょっとね、このサトウ様のごはんを。
There we go. Now, this Sato-sama's rice...
強い匂いは嫌だよ。
She hates strong smells.
玉ねぎは手につけてないし、あの...
I didn't get onions on my hands, and...
透明のやつでしかやってないから。
I only handled them with the transparent ones.
多分大丈夫だと思うんだけど。
I think it should be okay, but...
え、どうしよ、このホカホカのごはんを塔状（とうじょう）にするのってどうやってやったらいいんだ。
How am I supposed to make this piping hot
rice into a tower shape?
なんか勢い（いきおい）挟んでクロワッサン。
Somehow putting the croissants in
with momentum.
あ、これ、一回並べたのを、一回片付けて...
Ah, let me clear away the ones I lined up once...
美味そうだな、このクロワッサン。
This croissant looks delicious.
あ、こよりちゃんごめんね、めっちゃ伺ってる、敵を見る目で見ているこっちを。
Ah, sorry Koyori-chan, you're really watching...
you're looking at me like I'm an enemy.
ほぐして...
Loosen it up...
あ、カップに入れたら...
Ah, if I put it in a cup...
確かに、これじゃん！
True, this is it!
よいしょ、手袋外して...
Yoisho, taking off the gloves...
いや、プロテインカップはちょっとさすがにデカすぎるから...
No, the protein cup is a bit too big, as expected...
計量カップやん、お米の。ちょうどいいんじゃない、これ。
It's a measuring cup, for rice.
Isn't this just right?
これぐらいのさ、あの、高さじゃないと多分ぶち壊れちゃうよね。
If it's not about this height,
it'll probably fall apart.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
カップ溶かさないでね。そんなに熱くないだろう、お米って。
Don't melt the cup.
The rice shouldn't be that hot.
ね、そのぐらいならいいよね。
Right, if it's that much, it's fine.
しかもこれ180gだから、サトウのご飯これ200gだから、ちょうどいいか、ぎゅうぎゅうに詰めたら。
And this is 180g, and Sato's rice is 200g,
so maybe it's just right if I pack it in tightly.
めっちゃ熱そう。
Looks really hot.
大丈夫かな？
I wonder if it's okay?
え、全部詰めたい。200g、つまんないな。
Eh, I want to pack it all in.
200g... it won't fit.
ギュッと押したら入らないかな？
If I press it down hard, will it fit?
うーん、ちょっと余っちゃう。体積が違うよ。
Hmm, there's a bit left over.
The volume is different.
知ってた。知ってる。
I knew it. I know.
さすがに理系だから体積違うけど、いけないかなっていう望みを込めてたんだけど...
I'm a science major, so I know the volume is
different, but I was hoping anyway...
ちょっと違ったな。
It was a bit different.
ギュッ...
*Squeeze*
ちょっと余りはそのまま食べよう。
I'll just eat the leftovers as they are.
パクッ。え、これ出る？
*Munch* Eh, will this come out?
え、出ないやん！
Eh, it's not coming out!
え、出る？
Eh, will it come out?
あ、で...
Ah, it's...
やばい。
Oh no.
出る？
Will it come out?
あ、出たかも！あ、すごいすごいすごい！上手上手！
Ah, it might have come out! Ah, amazing amazing!
Good job, good job!
ギュッと押して...
Press it down...
え、見て！プリンみたいになった！
Eh, look! It became like a pudding!
お米が。
The rice.
すごくない？
Isn't it amazing?
こうやって作ってんのかな、ポケモンでも。
I wonder if they make it like this in Pokemon too.
ちょっとお米のまま食べ... あ、これ試食用に残しとこう、ちょっとお米ね。
I'll eat some rice as is...
Ah, let's save some rice for tasting.
こっちにかけて食べればちょうどいいね。
It'll be just right if I pour it over
this and eat.
じゃあ、写真用にこれ取っとける。
Then, I can save this for a photo.
懐かしのプリン、クリームプリンみたいになってる。
It looks like a nostalgic pudding,
like a cream pudding.
え、待ってみんな！58分なんだけど！
Eh, wait everyone! It's 58 minutes!
いいやん、ちょうどいいやん。
That's good, it's just right.
えー、これがね、計算通りってやつですね。
Eh, this is what you call "according to plan."
洗い物をして...
Doing the dishes...
ついに嫌われて、あ、でもついに横になってこっちなんか眺めてるから大丈夫そう。
Finally being hated...
Ah, but she's finally lying down and watching over here.
嫌われてはなさそう。
Doesn't seem like I'm hated.
で、お米を綺麗に盛り付けてる間に...
And while I'm plating the rice nicely...
12分ぐらいが多分経ちました。
About 12 minutes have probably passed.
よいしょ、計算通りですね、完全に。
Yoisho, completely according to plan.
では、最終的に味付けは...
Then, for the final seasoning...
なんか塩で加減を見ながらみたいな感じだったかな。
It was like checking the balance with salt, I think.
こより猫舌なんで、ちょっと大丈夫か心配なんですけど。
Koyori is sensitive to heat, so I'm a bit
worried if it's okay.
おお！おおー！
Oh! Ooh!
え、待ってなんか...
Eh, wait, something...
すごくない？
Isn't it amazing?
なんかこの赤い奴...
Something about this red one...
え、これ、え、何これどうしてこうなったの？
Eh, this, eh, what is this?
Why did it turn out like this?
赤いさ、汁、これインドカレー屋さん、本格インドカレー屋さんとかで頼んだ時に...
The red sauce, like when you order at
an authentic Indian curry shop...
出てくるビチョビチョ...
The runny stuff that comes out...
これ煮込んだら
If I simmer this,
ルーっぽくなるんじゃなかったんか？
wasn't it supposed to become more roux-like?
やばい、絶対にこれにやったら
Oh no, if I do this,
ベチャーってなるやん。
it'll definitely be all watery.
あれ？
Huh?
あれ？ スープカレー？
Huh? Soup curry?
あれ？ スープカレーじゃないはずなんだけど。
Wait, it's not supposed to be soup curry...
これでいいの？
Is this okay?
合ってるの？
Is it right?
合ってるのかなあ？
I wonder if it's right...
いや、もうちょっと見た目なんか
No, I thought it looked a bit more...
ヌメリあった気がするんだけど。
...viscous before.
あれ？ なんかおかしいけど、一旦塩入れてみましょう。
Huh? Something's off, but let's try adding salt for now.
塩。 まあ、まあ、入れないことはないでしょう、
Salt. Well, well, I guess I should put some in,
少々。
just a bit.
少々入れて...
Adding a bit...
これで加減見るか。
I'll check the seasoning with this.
あれ？ こういうもの？
Huh? Is it supposed to be like this?
水多かったかなあ。
Maybe there was too much water...
味見するのちょっと緊張するんだけど。
I'm a bit nervous about tasting it.
混ぜて。
Mixing it.
でもチキンはちゃんと煮込まれてそうです。
But the chicken looks properly simmered.
大丈夫そう。
It looks fine.
よし。
Alright.
小皿を出してきて、
Let me get a small dish,
ちょっと味見てみよう。
and taste it.
混ぜて。
Mixing.
ヨーグルトの水分？ そうかも。
Moisture from the yogurt? Maybe so.
え、ドキドキ。
Oh, I'm nervous.
ドキドキ。
Thump-thump.
え、でも匂いはめっちゃカレー。
But the smell is totally curry.
すごいスパイスのカレースパイスの香りがしてる。
It smells so much like curry spices.
ふむふむ。
Hmm, hmm.
いただきます。
Let's taste it.
美味しいよ！
It's delicious!
美味しい！
Delicious!
けど...
But...
なんかトマトの味が強い。
The tomato flavor is strong.
あれ？
Huh?
これチリソース入れてないだけだよね。
This is just because I haven't added the chili sauce, right?
塩もうちょっと。
A bit more salt.
これなんか物足りなく感じるのは
The reason it feels like something's missing
多分塩が足りないよね。
is probably because it needs more salt.
少々。
Just a bit.
え、だってさ、
Well, I mean,
これチリソースが足りないだけで...
it's just lacking chili sauce...
カレーじゃなくなる？
Will it stop being curry?
チキンのカレー風味
Like chicken simmered in tomato
トマト煮込みみたいな。
with a curry flavor.
感じになってる。
That's what it feels like.
入れるスパイス合ってます。
The spices I put in are correct.
合ってる。
They are.
まあ、普通に美味しいんだけど。
Well, it's tasty enough, but...
もうちょっと舐めてみよう。
Let's taste it a bit more.
とろみを入れるには何が必要なのかな。
What do I need to make it thicker?
あ、でも待って、
Oh, but wait,
なんかとろみ増えた気がしない？ 気のせい？
don't you think it's gotten thicker? Is it just me?
あの、分かった、今さ、蓋取ったじゃん。
I know, I took the lid off just now.
蓋取ったことにより、あの、
Because I took the lid off,
ちょっと水分が飛び始めて、
the moisture is starting to evaporate...
若干、あの、シャバシャバ感が
I feel like the watery sensation
減ってるような気がしてるんだけど。
has decreased slightly.
気のせい。
Just my imagination.
え、でも濃縮できそうな気がする、これ、
But I feel like it'll concentrate if
このままもうちょっと煮込んでたら。
I keep simmering it like this.
どうだろう。
I wonder.
え、でも蓋...
But the lid...
蓋するって書いてある。
It says to put the lid on.
でも、お味は美味しいです。
But the taste is delicious.
辛くなくて美味しい。
It's delicious and not spicy.
チリソースないからめっちゃ食べやすい。
Since there's no chili sauce, it's very easy to eat.
うめー。
Tasty.
うめーな。
Tasty, huh.
これは人に振る舞える味してるよ。
This is a taste I could serve to others.
カレーって言われそうだけど。
They'd probably say it's curry.
小麦粉入れよう。
Add flour.
本当に？
Really?
ほんまに言ってる？ 小麦粉ないわ。
Are you serious? I don't have flour.
うちに小麦粉なんちゅうものがあるわけなかった。
There's no way I'd have flour in my house.
ないよね。
I don't, right?
ないな。
I don't.
粉物... 粉か...
Flour... powder...
硬く... 待って、こっちかも。
It's hard... Wait, maybe it's here.
冷蔵庫じゃないわ。
It's not in the fridge.
あ、あるあるあるある！ 粉。
Ah, I found it! The powder.
粉セット、えー、創味シャンタン、コンソメ、
The powder set... uh, Soumi Shantan, consomme,
いりごま、ゆかり、丸鶏がらスープ... あ、待って、これじゃない？
roasted sesame, yukari, chicken stock... Oh wait, isn't it this?
あ！ あったあった！ 小麦粉！ ジャジャーン！ ありました！
Ah! Found it! Flour! Ta-da! Here it is!
え？ 何で？ 『やめとけ』？
Eh? Why? "Don't do it"?
え、結構『小麦粉推し』率高かったよ。
Eh, the percentage of people recommending flour was quite high.
え、待って待って待って。なんか阿鼻叫喚。
Eh, wait wait wait. It's like total chaos in chat.
『とろみ作って』
"Make it thick."
『入れないで。今からはダマになるよ』
"Don't add it. It'll get lumpy now."
『やめとけ』
"Don't do it."
あー、フライパンでスープ状にして...
Ah, making it into a soup in the frying pan...
『もう手遅れ。入れないほうがいいよ』
"It's too late. You shouldn't add it."
『絶対失敗する』
"You'll definitely fail."
何だよー、せっかく探したのにー。
What the heck, even though I went to the trouble of finding it.
まだどこに行ったかわかんなかった、緑と黄色の色素も出てきた。
I didn't even know where it went, and I found green and yellow food coloring too.
これにさ、緑色素入れたらグリーンカレーに見えるのかな？ 入れないけど。
I wonder if adding green coloring would make this look like green curry? I won't do it, though.
バター溶かして入れたら... バター入れても...
If I melt butter and add it... Even if I add butter...
あれじゃないかな？ シャバシャバ感は拭えなさそうな気がするけどね。
I don't think... I feel like I won't be able to get rid of the watery texture.
はい、ということで。
Alright, so.
え、味見はした。もう美味しい。
Uh, I did a taste test. It's already delicious.
次は盛り付けですね。
Next up is plating.
じゃあ、一回電源切って...
Well then, let's turn off the power...
一回IHの反射怖いからカメラを消して...
I'll turn off the camera for a second because I'm scared of the reflection from the IH...
『シナモンパウダーあるなら最後にちょこっと入れるといい』
"If you have cinnamon powder, it's good to add a little at the end."
え、シナモンパウダー入れていいの？ あるよ。
Eh, is it okay to add cinnamon powder? I have some.
こよちゃん好きだけど、シナモン。
Koyo likes cinnamon.
本当？ ちょいちょいさ、ワザップを掴まされて生きてきてるから...
Really? Because I've been living my life being fed hoaxes every now and then...
あ、待って。これそのまま置いたら熱いか。まあいいか。
Ah, wait. If I put this down like this, it'll be hot. Well, whatever.
カメラを越して... これはどうなってもいいやつだからね。
Moving the camera... This one is okay no matter what happens to it.
うーん、まあまあシャバシャバ... シャバシャバだから...
Hmm, it's pretty watery... Since it's watery...
これに盛った時に、洪水になっちゃいそうなのがまずいんだよな。
The problem is it looks like it'll flood the plate when I serve it.
一旦箸で...
First, with chopsticks...
お肉を載せる。
I'll place the meat.
あ、肉デカ！
Ah, the meat is huge!
一旦クロワッサンは... クロワッサンもシャバシャバになるやろ。
For now, the croissants... They'll probably get all soggy too.
やばい、肉が一個しか載らん。
Oh no, only one piece of meat will fit.
わかったわ。肉、肉、クロワッサン、肉、クロワッサンみたいにしよう。盛り付けね。
I've got it. Let's go with meat, meat, croissant, meat, croissant. For the plating.
ルーを... なるべくトロみがありそうなところを拾ってかける。
The roux... I'll scoop up the parts that look thickest and pour it on.
行けるか？
Can I do it?
いいかも
Looks good.
意外と... 玉ねぎが...
Surprisingly... the onions...
こびり付いてくれて
are sticking to it,
びしょびしょにならないかも
so it might not get soggy.
よいしょ
There we go.
いいーね
Nice.
あと、表面張力で置いておいた肉に...
Also, with surface tension, on the meat I laid out...
張力してくれてて
it's holding on with tension.
あ、ちょっと漏れ出してるところもあるけど...
Ah, it's leaking a little in some places, but...
なんかかかってる感じする
it feels like it's properly covered.
これ斜めにしたらもうね、終わるから
If I tilt this, it'll all be over,
写真でみんなに見せるしかないのがアレっすな
so showing you via photo is the only way.
ちょっと待って、ここら辺かけたい
Wait a sec, I want to pour some here.
写真で見えるところは綺麗にカレーをかけよう
Let's pour the curry neatly where it'll show in the photo.
はい、こうして
Okay, like this.
で、
And,
クロワッサンね
the croissants.
やばい！色が茶色！
Oh no! The color is so brown!
クロワッサン
Croissant.
クロ...
Cro...
できたー！
Done!
ちょっと待って、写真撮りたいなー
Wait a sec, I want to take a photo.
これでも背景、背景が映り込む...
Even so, the background... the background will be visible.
あ、待って待って待って！
Ah, wait wait wait!
パセリないからパセリ！
I don't have parsley! Parsley!
パセリがあった方が彩り...
It would look more colorful with parsley...
あ、パセリないかも
Ah, I might not have any.
待って、パセリ...
Wait, parsley...
ハーブミックスでいい？いいよ。オッケー
Is herb mix okay? It's fine. Okay.
これで...
With this...
お、いいやん！
Oh, nice!
彩り！
Colorful!
あ、見えてないなあんまりみんなに
Ah, you guys can't see it much.
え、でもちょっと待ってこれ今から写真撮るから
Wait, just a sec, I'm taking a photo now.
見せたい、見せたい、見せたい！
I want to show you, show you, show you!
ファビュラス、ファビュラス！
Fabulous, fabulous!
すごいファビュラスな感じになってる
It's looking very fabulous.
やっぱりこうやってまたこよちゃんは成功してしまうんだな
As expected, Koyo-chan succeeds once again.
待ってこれ背景黒がいいな
Wait, I want a black background for this.
ちょっと待って、黒持ってくるから
Wait a bit, I'll go get black.
ね、ちーちゃん
Right, Chi-chan?
よいしょ。いやーうまそううまそう
There. Man, it looks delicious.
いいやん！
Nice!
どうですかここよちゃん... 写真撮るからちょっと待って
How is it? ... I'm taking a photo, so wait a bit.
これ斜めから見るのが完成形だから
Looking from an angle is the final form,
これをみんなに見せるために今写真撮ってるからちょっと待って
so I'm taking a photo to show you all, wait a sec.
え、いいんじゃない？
Oh, isn't it good?
うまそう、うまそう
Looks delicious.
茶色いなー
It's so brown.
ま、カレーだからね。カレーって茶色いものだから
Well, it's curry. Curry is supposed to be brown.
ルーは後で足す
I'll add the roux later.
ここに送って...
Sending it here...
映える写真撮りましたんでちょっとお待ちください
I took a photogenic picture, so please wait a moment.
画像保存して...
Saving the image...
それを載せる
I'll post it.
これはちょっとね、みんな食べたくなって仕方なくなってしまうよ
This will definitely make everyone want to eat it.
できました！こちらです！
It's done! Here it is!
どうどうどうどう？
How is it? How is it?
茶色いけど。
It's quite brown, though.
なんか普通の色合いでも撮ったほうがいいかな？
Should I take a picture with normal colors too?
これ、あの「映える」写真、あの...
This is for that 'Insta-worthy' photo...
ご飯用のカメラで撮ってるから、色が濃いめになってるかも。
Since I'm using the food camera, the colors might look a bit dark.
普通のカメラで撮るか。
I'll take one with the normal camera.
上から見るより美味しそうでしょ？
It looks more delicious than looking from above, right?
写真撮りまして。ま、写真撮るの後でもよかったな。
Taken. Well, I could've taken the photo later.
さっきね、試食用にこれ取っておき... あ、見えない。
Earlier, I set this aside for a tasting... Oh, you can't see it.
試食用にこれ取っておきましたんで、これにかけて食べたいと思います。
I set this aside for tasting, so I'll put it on this and eat.
美味しいかな？
I wonder if it's good?
クロワッサンがメインに見える。
The croissants look like the main dish.
ま、クロワッサンカレーにしたから今日は。
Well, I made it croissant curry today.
それでは初めての本格スパイスカレー、食べてみたいと思います。
Now then, I'd like to try my first authentic spice curry.
あーん。
Ahhh.
めちゃくちゃ美味しいんだけど！
It's incredibly delicious!
なんでだろう？ チキンのトマト煮だなぁ。
Why is that? It tastes like chicken simmered in tomato.
なんでー！？
Whhyyy!?
なんで言われた通りにやったのに、
I did exactly as I was told,
なんでカレーになってないの！？
so why isn't it curry!?
チキンの... 待って、クロワッサン、クロワッサン食べよう。
It's chicken... Wait, the croissant, let's eat the croissant.
これにチリソース入れたところで、チキンのトマト煮っぽいな。
Even with chili sauce, it still tastes like chicken tomato stew.
うまいんだけどね！ 美味しいんだけど！
It's good, though! It is delicious!
これクロワッサンにそのまま直でかけて食べてみたいと思います。
I want to try putting it directly on the croissant and eating it.
いただきます。
Bon appétit.
うまい！ うまい！
It's good! It's good!
けど... カレー...
But... the curry...
クミン、どこ行った！？
Where did the cumin go!?
これってさ、ここから足して混ぜても味つく？
Hey, if I add more and mix it now, will it get the flavor?
クミン...
Cumin...
トマト煮込み...
Tomato stew...
粉っぽくなる？
Will it get powdery?
今じゃない？ やめといたほうがいい？
Not now? Is it better not to?
煮込めばいいわけだから
Since I just need to simmer it...
ガラムマサラ
Garam Masala.
ナツメグならあるんだけどな
I have nutmeg, though...
ちょっとグツグツ言わせて...
Let's let it bubble for a bit...
あ、でもちょっとあれかも、なんかとろみできてきたかも
Oh, but maybe... it looks like it's getting a bit thick.
ナツメグは違う
Nutmeg is different.
トマト、トマトスープっすね
It's like tomato... tomato soup.
あ、カレー、カレーです
Oh, it's curry, it's curry!
ほら、トマトスープカレーってあるじゃん、世の中に
See, tomato soup curry is a thing in the world, right?
これもまたカレーの形
This is also a form of curry.
ちょっと今、あの、グツグツしてますんで、少々お待ちください
It's simmering right now, so please wait a moment.
十分成功だよ、自信持って。ありがとう！
"It's a complete success, have confidence." Thank you!
いや、美味しいよ。普通に美味しいです
No, it's good. It's genuinely delicious.
普通に美味しい...
It's genuinely delicious...
けど...
But...
何でだろう？
I wonder why?
トマトピューレの量も間違ってないんだけどな
I didn't get the amount of tomato puree wrong either.
小さじが少なかったのかな？
Maybe the teaspoon amount was too small?
ココイチさん、ごめんカレー、やめてね
CoCo-Ichi, sorry for the curry... wait, don't say that.
何で謝罪から入らなきゃいけないんだよ。まだ出会ってもないのに
Why do I have to start with an apology? I haven't even met them yet.
ヨーグルトの量は、あの...
The amount of yogurt, well...
400gのやつしか売ってなかったから
Because they only sold 400g packs...
400gのヨーグルト買ってきて
I bought 400g of yogurt...
で、こうやって十字に割って
And then, I divided it into a cross like this...
4分の1だな、っていう量を入れた
And added what I thought was a quarter.
で、少ないよりは多い方がええやろ、と思って
And I thought it's better to have more than less.
ちょっと多めに、多分120gぐらい入れた
So I added a bit more, probably around 120g.
ヨーグルト、水切ってって書いてなかった
It didn't say to drain the yogurt.
何でその時、計量...
Why at that time, the measuring...
見つからなかったんだもん
I just couldn't find it.
肉の仕込みのさ、ヨーグルトぐらい、量大丈夫だと思うじゃん
You'd think the amount of yogurt for preparing the meat would be fine, right?
今までそうやって生きてきた。ちょっとクミン入れますね
That's how I've lived my life until now. I'll add a little cumin.
煮込み、煮込み...
Simmering, simmering...
ターメリック足すのはどうなんだろう？
I wonder if I should add some turmeric?
までも美味しいから成功なんですけどね
Well, it tastes good, so it's a success regardless.
誰が何と言おうと
No matter what anyone says.
ターメリックは味ない
Turmeric doesn't have a taste.
コリアンダーは？
What about coriander?
ま、さっきクミン足せって言われたから、クミン足すのが正解か
Well, since I was told to add cumin earlier, I guess adding cumin is the right move.
クミン足して、混ぜて
Add cumin, and stir.
ちょっと今、水分が抜けていっていて
The moisture is evaporating now...
味見
Taste test.
あっ！えっ！
Ah! What?!
もうカレーになった！待って！えっ！
It's already become curry! Wait! What?!
ちょっと待って、これ、騙されてると思うかも、みんな。ちょっと待って、これ演技力じゃない
Wait a minute, you guys might think I'm kidding. Wait, this isn't acting!
え、カレーになった！
Wh- It turned into curry!
え、嘘、クミンちょっと入れただけで？
What? No way, just from adding a bit of cumin?
え、多分しかも今ね、煮込んでることで、本当にね、ちょっと水分飛んでとろみが...
And probably because it's simmering now, the water is evaporating and the thickness...
増した。え、クミンってすげえ！
Has increased. Wow, cumin is amazing!
え、クミンの力感じたわ
I really felt the power of cumin.
待って、クミンってウコンじゃん
Wait, cumin is turmeric, right?
違うわ
No, it's not.
ウコンはターメリックだ
Turmeric is ukon.
ええ！すごいすごいすごいすごい！え、すごい！
Whoa! Amazing, amazing, amazing! Wow, this is great!
でももう、この子はここで完成しちゃってるから
But since this one is already finished here...
どうしよ、追い、追い掛けするか
What should I do? Maybe add a bit... add a bit more on top?
追い掛けしよう
Let's add more on top.
え、ウコンの力がさ、クミンの力だったんかってなったけど、あ、違ったわ
I thought the 'Power of Ukon' was actually the 'Power of Cumin' for a second, but ah, I was wrong.
はい。こうして、こうして...
Okay. Like this, and like this...
かける。
Pouring it on.
追い掛けして。写真もいっぱい撮ったし、
I'll pour some more on. I've taken lots of photos,
追い掛けしてこれで食べたら...
so now I'll pour extra and eat it...
ドロドロになった！ええやんええやん、ええやん！
It's got so thick! This is good, good, good!
これでちょっと食べてみたいと思います。直で。
I'm going to try eating it now. Straight up.
チキンがデカすぎて乗らないんで、このまま...
The chicken is too big to fit on the spoon, so...
煮詰まった！煮込まないと...
It's thickened! You really have to simmer it...
そうだよ、カレーって一日煮込んだカレーとか...
That's right, they say curry that's been
simmered for a day...
煮込まないとダメなんだ。
You have to simmer it.
カレーだ！！
It's curry!!
すごい！ちーちゃんカレーできたよ！
Incredible! Chii-chan, I made curry!
落ちかけ入ってるわ。
Some spilled in.
カレーだ、カレー、カレー、カレー！
みんなできた！成功、成功、成功！
It's curry, curry, curry, curry!
I did it, everyone! Success, success, success!
マジで本当に、これ食べてほしい！
Seriously, I want you to eat this!
誰かもう一人欲しかった、ここに！
I wish there was someone else here with me!
マジで変わったことを伝えたい！
I really want to convey how much it's changed!
伝えたいわ、食べてほしいマジで。
I want to share it, I really want you to eat it.
こんなことある？
Is this even possible?
みんなも本格スパイスカレーに挑戦して、
Everyone, try making authentic spice curry,
シャバシャバだったなと思ったら...
and if you think it's too watery...
まず水分が抜けるくらい煮込んでください。
First, simmer it until the water evaporates.
で、食べて「あれ？トマトの味強っ」
Then, eat it and go, "Wait, the tomato is strong."
「何これ？トマトチキン煮込みやん」と思ったら、
"What's this? It's just stewed tomato chicken."
クミン足す！よろしくお願いします。
Then add cumin! Please remember that.
え、だってこれさ、もう違いを比べられないもん。
I mean, look, you can't even compare
the difference now.
うわああああああ！すごい！
Uwaaaaaaaa! Incredible!
鶏肉も食べてみよう。
Let's try the chicken too.
この鶏肉はこのカレールーでは炒められてないけど。
This chicken wasn't stir-fried in
this specific curry roux, though.
お姉さんのご飯の器をお皿にして。
Using my sister's rice bowl as a plate.
うめえええ！！
Delicious!!
これほどクミンはかなり味をまとめるんだ。
Cumin really brings the flavor together
that much.
すごいね。あんなちょっとピュって入れただけなのに。
Amazing. Even though I only added
a little dash of it.
クミンに感謝ね。クミンの偉大さを知りましたわ。
Thanks to cumin. I've learned
how great cumin is.
かけて...
Pouring it on...
このまま、このクロワッサンかじりたいと思います。
Now, I'm going to bite into this croissant.
ちょっと甘いけど。
It's a little sweet, though.
ちょっと、クロワッサンの甘みが気になるけど...
I'm a bit concerned about the sweetness
of the croissant, but...
うめえええ！！
Delicious!!
失敗を認めよう。いや、違いますね、これは。
Let's acknowledge the failure. No, wait, that's wrong.
研究者ならではの...
This is typical of a researcher...
失敗を認めたからこその、そこからの改善成功！
Because I acknowledged failure, I could succeed
in improving it!
あれですよ、ペニシリンを発見した時と一緒です！
It's just like when penicillin was discovered!
科学者の勝利ということです。
It's a victory for science.
うまあああい！カレーだ、カレーだ！
So goooood! It's curry, it's curry!
一回は失敗した。一回は失敗したけど、
I failed once. I failed once, but...
結果良ければ全て良しなんで。これは成功！
All's well that ends well.
This is a success!
アンケート終了したいと思います。
I'll close the poll now.
えー、アンケート。
Uh, the poll results.
「成功する」に入れたのが62%。
「失敗するかも」に入れたのが38%。
62% voted for "Success."
38% voted for "Might fail."
38%の皆さん、これ見たかああああ！！
To the 38%, did you see this?!!
ざまああああ！！
Take thaaaaat!!
こよりがペニシリンや！！
Koyori is Penicillin!!
いやー、すごい。歴史だな。
Wow, incredible. This is history.
クミンの偉大さを発見してしまった、もしやこれ。
I've discovered the greatness of cumin.
ノーベル賞ものかも...
This might be Nobel Prize material...
しかもね、このクロワッサンカレーも...
And you know, this croissant curry too...
作中で、あれだけ微妙な扱い受けてたから...
Since it was treated so poorly in the manga...
美味しくないのかなと思ったけど、普通に美味しいしな。
I thought it wouldn't be good,
but it's actually delicious.
まあちょっとカロリー高いけど。
Well, the calories are a bit high, though.
米もあれだけあるのに、さらにクロワッサンまで...
I have all that rice, and then
croissants on top...
食うの大変やなって感じではあるけどね、三つもあるから。
It's quite a lot to eat, especially
with three of them.
（食べる音）んー、んー。
(Eating sounds) Mhm, mhm.
ということでね。えー、皆さん、本日はこよりちゃんの
So then, everyone, today was Koyori-chan's...
本格スパイスカレー作り、初めての本格スパイスカレー作りを見ていただき
...authentic spice curry making, thank you for watching my first authentic spice curry making!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
大成功いたしましたので、
It was a huge success,
ね、こちらですね、あのー、
so, this one, um...
ぜひ真似して作ってみていただければと
please try making it yourself by following this,
思いまーす！
I hope you will!
そして、え、あの、ハッシュタグ「#こより実験中」をつけて
And, um, please use the hashtag #KoyoriExperimenting...
「こよちゃんカレー超期待」は…
...to say "Koyo-chan's curry is super promising"...
食べ散らかし汚いから、
Wait, the way I'm eating is a mess, so...
「こよちゃんカレー大成功！」
..."Koyo-chan's curry was a huge success!"
「初めてで本格スパイスカレーを成功させるなんて、すごい！」
"To succeed with authentic spice curry on your first try, you're amazing!"
っつって、画面のスクショも載せて、
Say that, and post a screenshot of the screen,
えー、いっぱい感想をね、呟いて、
and tweet lots of your thoughts,
あの、ちょっとオーディション…
um, to help me pass the audition...
オーディション合格できるように、ちょっと応援をよろしくお願いします！
Please support me so I can pass the audition! (Laughs)
オーディションではない。はい、すみません。
It's not an audition. Yes, sorry.
ちょっとたまたまね、タイミングがものすごく合ってしまったがゆえに、
The timing just happened to be really coincidental, so...
あの、いっぱい弄っちゃってすみませんでした。
...um, I'm sorry for teasing you so much.
ゴエさん、すみませんでした。よかったら、あの、今後ともよろしくお願いいたします。
Goe-san, I'm sorry. I look forward to working with you in the future.
ということで、こよりはちょっと温かいうちにカレー食べたいんで、
So, Koyori wants to eat her curry while it's still warm,
締めたいと思いまーす！
...so I'll wrap things up!
チャンネル登録、高評価まだの方はポチッと押してください。よろしくお願いします。
If you haven't subscribed or liked the video yet, please click the button. Thank you!
いや、マジでよかった。チキンのトマト煮で終わらなくてよかった。
No, but really, it was great. I'm glad it didn't just end with tomato-stewed chicken.
失敗からのゴリ押しでの成功、素晴らしい。ありがとう！
Pushing through failure to success is wonderful. Thank you!
ほな、またねー！
Well then, see you later!
Thank you for watching!
[Visual: Thank you for watching!]
Subscribe to my channel / Click The Like button ♡
[Visual: Subscribe to my channel / Click The Like button ♡]
Follow me on Twitter @HakuiKoyori
[Visual: Follow me on Twitter @HakuiKoyori]
See you next time!
[Visual: See you next time!]
また会いに来てね！
Come see me again!
クロワッサンはそのまま食べた方がやっぱうまいわ。
Croissants really do taste better on their own.
カレーはカレー、クロワッサンはクロワッサン。
Curry is curry, and croissants are croissants.
いやな、ちょっと気持ちがわかったわ。えへ。
Yeah, I think I understand the feeling now. Ehe.